<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Minimalist Setup on AshLee&#39;s Random Blog Space</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/minimalist-setup/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Minimalist Setup on AshLee&#39;s Random Blog Space</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/minimalist-setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>My Own Take on Digital Minimalism and Why Is It Aligns With My Privacy &amp; Security stand</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/digital-minimalism-ramble/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/digital-minimalism-ramble/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/p/digital-minimalism-ramble/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My Own Take on Digital Minimalism and Why Is It Aligns With My Privacy &amp; Security stand" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to finish a lot of articles for my little blog over the last two years. This one feels important to me, as instead of talking about tips &amp;amp; tricks or writing guides, I talk about my own philosophy and political(?) view. Hopefully, it’ll be easier to finish as it’s an opinion piece and less depends on research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be CLEAR, I’m a tech LOVER! Because I’m a tech lover, I came to take digital minimalism as a way of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was tempted to write this post as I’ve seen some videos of people switching to “dumb phones” in order to not use social medias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, that idea isn’t bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only have 2 concerns:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Those devices use old Android versions and can cost security issues and are easy to hack and send viruses to. I can’t recommend wholeheartedly to switch to “dumb phones” knowing this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t need those devices to detox yourself. You don’t need to get vulnerable ￼in your security in order to live without socials. Security isn’t the price for digital privacy. You can use your &lt;strong&gt;current&lt;/strong&gt; device and still detox yourself!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do want to get a flip phone for the aesthetic of things (bitch gets it!), &lt;em&gt;ALT MIVE Style Folder&lt;/em&gt; is a phone that runs Android 12/Android 14 (depends if you buy Folder 1 or Folder 2). I’m unsure about how long it receives security updates, as I can’t find information online. If any of you live in Korea, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to share my own piece and how I live my life without using my phone as much and how I protect my privacy and security. Without further ado, let’s start this article!~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-digital-minimalism&#34;&gt;What is Digital Minimalism?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s pull the AI definition y’all!! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Minimalism&lt;/strong&gt; is a philosophy that advocates for a more intentional and minimalist approach to technology use. It emphasises simplicity, clarity, and focus in the digital world. Proponents of digital minimalism aim to eliminate distractions, reduce screen time, and cultivate healthier relationships with technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key principles of digital minimalism include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intentional technology use&lt;/strong&gt;: Using technology with a clear purpose and intention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplifying digital tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Reducing the number of apps, accounts, and digital clutter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritising offline activities&lt;/strong&gt;: Focusing on real-world experiences and face-to-face interactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embracing digital boundaries&lt;/strong&gt;: Setting limits on screen time, notifications, and online engagement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By adopting digital minimalism, individuals can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improve mental clarity&lt;/strong&gt; and reduce stress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase productivity&lt;/strong&gt; and focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhance creativity&lt;/strong&gt; and inspiration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foster deeper connections&lt;/strong&gt; with others and the world around them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I personally took this: Have as minimum apps in my phone as possible and occasionally delete what’s unneeded. Preferably to self host as much services as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-digital-minimalism&#34;&gt;Why Digital Minimalism?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know all the philosophy behind it, live happier life, be more focused and mindful in your life, be more productive, yada yada. Sure, it’s important! But my main reason was that the less apps I have, the less things I need to maintain for my security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The less apps I have, the less digital footprint I have, the more private life I live. Less likely for my information to get stolen and sold in security breaches, less being sold into&amp;hellip; You get the idea!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s disadvantages for it, I work in the creative field and the decision not to use Instagram affects how I can market myself and find clients. I have less connection with my peers as they keep track of each other on socials. However, it’s a price I’m willing to pay, besides, the people who I care about know how to reach me and talk to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m telling you all this so you’ll know that this path isn’t sunshine and rainbows, it has pros and cons like anything else in life. You just need to decide if it’s something you’re willing to pay or not. Go ask yourself, your family, your friends, your lover, your therapist, your pet(?) before making a decision!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just know that you can always change things if it doesn’t suit you, it’s not a catholic marriage! Digital Minimalism is a spectrum, do what makes you happy and serves you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-it-related-to-privsec&#34;&gt;How Is It Related To Privsec?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the decisions I make on my digital life are related to Privsec. Privacy rights are something I believe in and fight for. For me, digital minimalism and Privsec goes hand in hand!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how digital minimalism is related to PrivSec (with more AI junk!):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduce data collection&lt;/strong&gt;: By using fewer apps and services, you can minimise the amount of personal data you share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimise tracking&lt;/strong&gt;: Digital minimalism can help you avoid tracking cookies, online ads, and other forms of surveillance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protect against cyber threats&lt;/strong&gt;: Digital minimalism can help you avoid phishing scams, malware, and other types of cyber threats by being more cautious about the links you click and the apps they download.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer to self host as much as I can. Not only that it puts me in control over my data, it puts me in control over my services security. Obviously, it’s not for everyone, yet if you’re tech savvy, I recommend looking into self hosting. I am writing a guide how to self host for cheap, it’ll be done soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;any-advice-for-cutting-apps-away&#34;&gt;Any Advice For Cutting Apps Away?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly? My biggest advice is to delete the apps. You’ll have a few hard weeks where you’ll need to fill the urge of using socials or the news (or whichever app you’re addicted to!), but I assure you it gets easier in time and this too shall pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to fill that urge? My biggest trick is to get into journalling! When I cut off Twitter back at 2020, instead of writing what’s happening to me and my feelings on Twitter, I used a little notebook instead! I always carry a notebook and a sketchbook in my bag and when I can, I take it out and write or draw.￼&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know people who have a retro handheld in their pocket or bag and they take it out to play games in their pocket of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re still struggling with cutting apps/websites away, StayFocusd is a Chromium plugin, Android app and iOS app which helps you block apps and websites and put time limits on them. I use it a lot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my iPhone, I use the default screen time option for app limits. But on my Mac and my old Android device, I use StayFocusd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wanna check how’s your friends doing through socials, maybe give them a call to ask how they’re doing or message them? If they’re friends only on socials, ask them if you can talk somewhere else?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this path isn’t sunshine and rainbows, cutting away people you see on socials is a price, not to mention your short-term sanity. Another aspect is that you might not see content you love, at least not as often. For me, the pros overweight the cons, however, for you it might be different and that’s OKAY!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-want-my-kid-to-use-their-phone-less-but-i-dont-want-to-eliminate-their-right-for-privacy&#34;&gt;I Want My Kid to Use Their Phone Less But I Don’t Want to Eliminate Their Right for Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write this little section here because it feels important to me and related enough. (Y’know, digital minimalism, creating apps &amp;amp; websites limits&amp;hellip; It made sense.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not a parent, I was a child once in the digital era, though. Does it make me an expert? No. But I can share my opinion like anybody else who lives online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a thin line between respecting your child’s right for privacy yet monitoring their phones and how they use it. I think having a conversation with your child about those things should help, they’re more understanding than you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can only provide tools, how they’re used depends on your family dynamic. Just please make sure to have a conversation with your child before introducing any drastic change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s apps like StayFocusd which are targeted towards families. As a parent, you can see which apps your child has on their device and put time limits on them. (For example, those apps will be blocked when they’re at school and after school activities and can only be used for an hour a day.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On iOS, you can achieve it on screen time menu. You can set screen time for family and set up parental control. There, you should be able to tweak settings and monitor your child accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another suggestion is to ask your child for their phone in order to set their social profiles as minors and put your credentials for their safety in case something goes wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;80% of this blog post was written in one sitting because I was fed up with people saying why doomscrolling isn’t as simple as uninstalling apps and why you should buy flip phones instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think you need to buy a new device that cost 130$ to 350+$. Not everyone can afford it, especially if your phone still works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution for being addicted to socials and doomscrolling is simple, it’s emotionally draining like any battle against addiction, nonetheless, it’s simple. I don’t think buying a new device makes the lack of dopamine easier, despite how nostalgic and sentimental it makes you feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So before rushing to spend your hard earned money on a new phone, I hope this article will give you a new perspective and a way to live your digital life more happily.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
