<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Security on AshLee&#39;s Random Blog Space</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/security/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Security on AshLee&#39;s Random Blog Space</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 08:32:53 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The magic of Front-ended socials (and how to end doom-scrolling and still watch your favourite content)</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-magic-of-front-ended-socials-and-how-to-end-doom-scrolling-and-still-watch-your-favourite-content/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 08:32:53 +0300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-magic-of-front-ended-socials-and-how-to-end-doom-scrolling-and-still-watch-your-favourite-content/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/p/the-magic-of-front-ended-socials-and-how-to-end-doom-scrolling-and-still-watch-your-favourite-content/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The magic of Front-ended socials (and how to end doom-scrolling and still watch your favourite content)" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many times I realise that stuff that are obvious to me aren’t obvious to others. (To be fair, a lot of shit that’s obvious to you isn’t obvious to me, &lt;abbr title=&#34;Laugh out loud&#34;&gt;LOL&lt;/abbr&gt;!) When those moments hit, my brain goes: “let’s spread my knowledge around so more people will be aware!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This struck me yesterday when I spoke with a friend about Tiktok and brainrot from Tiktok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me, like the major douche I am, went: “uninstall TikTok!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How will I watch my favourite tiktokers then?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that moment, I was struck with a major “oh” moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh. People aren’t aware of Tiktok frontends&amp;hellip; Or frontends for social medias in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yes, I’m writing a blog post about it so I could share it with people. Don’t worry, normies, I got chu! I’ll save you from doomscrolling!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is going to have links, both for the projects source codes + instances I use. I am planning to self host those frontends at some point, I just procrastinate a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-the-fuck-is-a-front-ended-social-media&#34;&gt;What the fuck is a front-ended social media?!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frontend alternatives for social media platforms are designed to provide a more privacy-friendly and ad-free experience. These alternatives often use the &lt;abbr title=&#34;Application Programming Interface&#34;&gt;API&lt;/abbr&gt;s or scrape data from the original social media services but present it in a cleaner, more user-friendly format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These alternatives aim to enhance user privacy and reduce intrusive elements like ads and tracking scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;socials-and-their-front-ends&#34;&gt;Socials and their front-ends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an overview of frontend alternatives, please check this &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/mendel5/alternative-front-ends&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still here? Nice! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;instagram&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://imginn.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;imginn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self hosted?&lt;/strong&gt; Not that I can tell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Github Page:&lt;/strong&gt; Not that I could find&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instance I use:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://imginn.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://imginn.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tiktok&#34;&gt;Tiktok&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://proxitok.pussthecat.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Proxitok&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self hosted?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Github Page:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/pablouser1/ProxiTok&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/pablouser1/ProxiTok&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instance I use:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://proxitok.pussthecat.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://proxitok.pussthecat.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://nitter.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Nitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self hosted?&lt;/strong&gt; Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Github Page:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/zedeus/nitter&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/zedeus/nitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instance I use:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://nitter.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://nitter.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;youtube&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TubeArchivist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self hosted?&lt;/strong&gt; Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Github Page:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/tubearchivist/tubearchivist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instance I use:&lt;/strong&gt; My own self hosted version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably nobody but my friends will read this shit. But if you’ve read this and came out with new knowledge, I did my job!~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would recommend to create a list of the usernames of your favourite content creators on social medias, keep it in a document file, then search them on the frontends. You can also save their frontend instance link on that document and every once in a while check for new content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s slower to consume content that way, but you won’t be as stimulated and &lt;em&gt;allegedly&lt;/em&gt; live a more peaceful life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!~ See you at some point!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to Make a Jellyfin Music Player for Cheap</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/how-to-make-a-diy-musicplayer/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/how-to-make-a-diy-musicplayer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/p/how-to-make-a-diy-musicplayer/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to Make a Jellyfin Music Player for Cheap" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might call me impulsive and crazy, but one of the only things I miss from Android is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.symfonium.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Symfonium&lt;/a&gt;, it’s the best music player app for people who self host. It supports Jellyfin and Subsonic and local music and is one of the few music players that feels &lt;em&gt;complete.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;abbr title=&#34;iPhone Operating System&#34;&gt;iOS&lt;/abbr&gt; Jellyfin apps don’t compare to the experience &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.symfonium.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Symfonium&lt;/a&gt; gave me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to make a &lt;abbr title=&#34;Do It Yourself&#34;&gt;DIY&lt;/abbr&gt; music player and pretend it’s the early 2000’s! :) It’s pretty cheap so I hope you’ll make it! I do software tweaking to fit my needs but you don’t need to follow everything to make this work, do what serve you and makes you comfortable! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-need&#34;&gt;What You Need?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A miniature phone (you can buy one for cheap on Aliexpress or Amazon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera cover stickers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;abbr title=&#34;Personal Computer&#34;&gt;PC&lt;/abbr&gt; (Windows/Linux/MacOS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Universal Android Debloater&#34;&gt;UAD&lt;/abbr&gt; &lt;abbr title=&#34;Graphical User Interface&#34;&gt;GUI&lt;/abbr&gt; installed on your &lt;abbr title=&#34;Personal Computer&#34;&gt;PC&lt;/abbr&gt; - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/0x192/universal-android-debloater&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/0x192/universal-android-debloater&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/Universal-Debloater-Alliance/universal-android-debloater-next-generation/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/Universal-Debloater-Alliance/universal-android-debloater-next-generation/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-0---cover-the-devices-cameras&#34;&gt;Step 0 - Cover the device’s cameras.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just in case. My device runs Android 10 and I couldn’t take any risks so I covered the cameras with specialised stickers I ordered from Aliexpress. If I could, I would break the microphone, but alas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1---debloating-the-miniature-phone&#34;&gt;Step 1 - Debloating the miniature phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those phones come with basic apps installed and quite a bit of bloat. If you’ve ordered something similar to mine, you’ve got 16GB of storage and 2GB of &lt;abbr title=&#34;Random-access memory&#34;&gt;RAM&lt;/abbr&gt;. Yeah&amp;hellip; Not a lot&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First step is to enable developer mode, clicking on build number several times should do the trick. Next, enter developer options and enable &lt;em&gt;USB debugging.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second step, connect the device to your &lt;abbr title=&#34;Personal Computer&#34;&gt;PC&lt;/abbr&gt; and open &lt;abbr title=&#34;Universal Android Debloater&#34;&gt;UAD&lt;/abbr&gt; software, the name of the device should appear on top of the program alongside a list of apps you can uninstall/disable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read carefully through the list and uninstall unnecessary bloat. It takes a lot of trial and error to know which bloat might break your device, so don’t feel alarmed to uninstall and reinstall things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After debloating your phone, put your phone on airplane mode and then connect to your wifi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airplane mode enhances privacy by turning off all wireless connections on your phone, including cellular networks, Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, and &lt;abbr title=&#34;Global Positioning System&#34;&gt;GPS&lt;/abbr&gt;. This prevents your device from transmitting or receiving any signals, thereby reducing the amount of data that can be collected about your location and activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airplane mode also saves battery life, you could solely waste it on listening to music! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2---install-symfonium&#34;&gt;Step 2 - Install &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.symfonium.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Symfonium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed it through the Google Play store. I paid for the program so I wanted to have access to it. I also wanted automatic updates. It was a risk I was willing to take. You can download it through Aurora Store, if you want, and using Google Play Store and Google Services is against your &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.privacyguides.org/en/basics/threat-modeling/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;threat model&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3---set-symfonium-up-and-enjoy-3&#34;&gt;Step 3 - Set &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.symfonium.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Symfonium&lt;/a&gt; up and Enjoy! :3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open the app, follow the process in the screen and enjoy your new music player!! :) I also added &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.symfonium.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Symfonium&lt;/a&gt; widget on the home screen to give it more of a music player vibe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I connected a &lt;abbr title=&#34;Micro Secure Digital&#34;&gt;MicroSD&lt;/abbr&gt; card to have more space for my music. I used 128GB, but I think 64GB or 32GB is enough. It’s up to how large your library is and how much music you wanna download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend going through the settings on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.symfonium.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Symfonium&lt;/a&gt; to tweak the interface and setup automatic downloads! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bonus-step---download-nova-launcher&#34;&gt;Bonus Step - Download Nova Launcher&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write this 24ish hours after initial setup! I got sick of the homepage: having apps scattered around all the home screen and I needed a better grid for my widgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nova launcher is super easy to install and use. I’ve been using them for years at this point. I put cute image as a widget + &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.symfonium.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Symfonium&lt;/a&gt; music player widget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/how-to-make-a-diy-musicplayer/Screenshot_20250416-002047.png&#34;
	width=&#34;452&#34;
	height=&#34;960&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/how-to-make-a-diy-musicplayer/Screenshot_20250416-002047_hu_851df75c8bfd9260.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/p/how-to-make-a-diy-musicplayer/Screenshot_20250416-002047_hu_56a1c8f4a42a9f9.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The aesthetic I went with was retro cybercore with lots of anime waifus, hehe.&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;47&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;113px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a fun &lt;abbr title=&#34;Do It Yourself&#34;&gt;DIY&lt;/abbr&gt; “iPod” project which doesn’t cost a lot. The 2GB of &lt;abbr title=&#34;Random-access memory&#34;&gt;RAM&lt;/abbr&gt; is surprisingly enough, although I internally wish it had 4GB to avoid lag&amp;hellip; ):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please support &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.symfonium.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Symfonium&lt;/a&gt; developers by donating or purchasing the app if you can! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only complaint in this &lt;abbr title=&#34;Do It Yourself&#34;&gt;DIY&lt;/abbr&gt; is that I can’t connect my headphones through &lt;abbr title=&#34;Universal Serial Bus&#34;&gt;USB&lt;/abbr&gt; C and have to use my Bluetooth ones, I looked over and over again on my disabled apps but couldn’t find a source for it and Google wasn’t helpful either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll finish this article with: be careful when debloating and don’t go overkill like yours truly! Don’t panic though as everything is reversible! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My Own Take on Digital Minimalism and Why Is It Aligns With My Privacy &amp; Security stand</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/digital-minimalism-ramble/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/digital-minimalism-ramble/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/p/digital-minimalism-ramble/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My Own Take on Digital Minimalism and Why Is It Aligns With My Privacy &amp; Security stand" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to finish a lot of articles for my little blog over the last two years. This one feels important to me, as instead of talking about tips &amp;amp; tricks or writing guides, I talk about my own philosophy and political(?) view. Hopefully, it’ll be easier to finish as it’s an opinion piece and less depends on research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be CLEAR, I’m a tech LOVER! Because I’m a tech lover, I came to take digital minimalism as a way of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was tempted to write this post as I’ve seen some videos of people switching to “dumb phones” in order to not use social medias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, that idea isn’t bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only have 2 concerns:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Those devices use old Android versions and can cost security issues and are easy to hack and send viruses to. I can’t recommend wholeheartedly to switch to “dumb phones” knowing this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t need those devices to detox yourself. You don’t need to get vulnerable ￼in your security in order to live without socials. Security isn’t the price for digital privacy. You can use your &lt;strong&gt;current&lt;/strong&gt; device and still detox yourself!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do want to get a flip phone for the aesthetic of things (bitch gets it!), &lt;em&gt;ALT MIVE Style Folder&lt;/em&gt; is a phone that runs Android 12/Android 14 (depends if you buy Folder 1 or Folder 2). I’m unsure about how long it receives security updates, as I can’t find information online. If any of you live in Korea, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to share my own piece and how I live my life without using my phone as much and how I protect my privacy and security. Without further ado, let’s start this article!~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-digital-minimalism&#34;&gt;What is Digital Minimalism?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s pull the AI definition y’all!! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Minimalism&lt;/strong&gt; is a philosophy that advocates for a more intentional and minimalist approach to technology use. It emphasises simplicity, clarity, and focus in the digital world. Proponents of digital minimalism aim to eliminate distractions, reduce screen time, and cultivate healthier relationships with technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key principles of digital minimalism include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intentional technology use&lt;/strong&gt;: Using technology with a clear purpose and intention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplifying digital tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Reducing the number of apps, accounts, and digital clutter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritising offline activities&lt;/strong&gt;: Focusing on real-world experiences and face-to-face interactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embracing digital boundaries&lt;/strong&gt;: Setting limits on screen time, notifications, and online engagement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By adopting digital minimalism, individuals can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improve mental clarity&lt;/strong&gt; and reduce stress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase productivity&lt;/strong&gt; and focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhance creativity&lt;/strong&gt; and inspiration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foster deeper connections&lt;/strong&gt; with others and the world around them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I personally took this: Have as minimum apps in my phone as possible and occasionally delete what’s unneeded. Preferably to self host as much services as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-digital-minimalism&#34;&gt;Why Digital Minimalism?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know all the philosophy behind it, live happier life, be more focused and mindful in your life, be more productive, yada yada. Sure, it’s important! But my main reason was that the less apps I have, the less things I need to maintain for my security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The less apps I have, the less digital footprint I have, the more private life I live. Less likely for my information to get stolen and sold in security breaches, less being sold into&amp;hellip; You get the idea!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s disadvantages for it, I work in the creative field and the decision not to use Instagram affects how I can market myself and find clients. I have less connection with my peers as they keep track of each other on socials. However, it’s a price I’m willing to pay, besides, the people who I care about know how to reach me and talk to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m telling you all this so you’ll know that this path isn’t sunshine and rainbows, it has pros and cons like anything else in life. You just need to decide if it’s something you’re willing to pay or not. Go ask yourself, your family, your friends, your lover, your therapist, your pet(?) before making a decision!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just know that you can always change things if it doesn’t suit you, it’s not a catholic marriage! Digital Minimalism is a spectrum, do what makes you happy and serves you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-it-related-to-privsec&#34;&gt;How Is It Related To Privsec?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the decisions I make on my digital life are related to Privsec. Privacy rights are something I believe in and fight for. For me, digital minimalism and Privsec goes hand in hand!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how digital minimalism is related to PrivSec (with more AI junk!):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduce data collection&lt;/strong&gt;: By using fewer apps and services, you can minimise the amount of personal data you share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimise tracking&lt;/strong&gt;: Digital minimalism can help you avoid tracking cookies, online ads, and other forms of surveillance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protect against cyber threats&lt;/strong&gt;: Digital minimalism can help you avoid phishing scams, malware, and other types of cyber threats by being more cautious about the links you click and the apps they download.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer to self host as much as I can. Not only that it puts me in control over my data, it puts me in control over my services security. Obviously, it’s not for everyone, yet if you’re tech savvy, I recommend looking into self hosting. I am writing a guide how to self host for cheap, it’ll be done soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;any-advice-for-cutting-apps-away&#34;&gt;Any Advice For Cutting Apps Away?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly? My biggest advice is to delete the apps. You’ll have a few hard weeks where you’ll need to fill the urge of using socials or the news (or whichever app you’re addicted to!), but I assure you it gets easier in time and this too shall pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to fill that urge? My biggest trick is to get into journalling! When I cut off Twitter back at 2020, instead of writing what’s happening to me and my feelings on Twitter, I used a little notebook instead! I always carry a notebook and a sketchbook in my bag and when I can, I take it out and write or draw.￼&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know people who have a retro handheld in their pocket or bag and they take it out to play games in their pocket of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re still struggling with cutting apps/websites away, StayFocusd is a Chromium plugin, Android app and iOS app which helps you block apps and websites and put time limits on them. I use it a lot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my iPhone, I use the default screen time option for app limits. But on my Mac and my old Android device, I use StayFocusd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wanna check how’s your friends doing through socials, maybe give them a call to ask how they’re doing or message them? If they’re friends only on socials, ask them if you can talk somewhere else?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this path isn’t sunshine and rainbows, cutting away people you see on socials is a price, not to mention your short-term sanity. Another aspect is that you might not see content you love, at least not as often. For me, the pros overweight the cons, however, for you it might be different and that’s OKAY!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-want-my-kid-to-use-their-phone-less-but-i-dont-want-to-eliminate-their-right-for-privacy&#34;&gt;I Want My Kid to Use Their Phone Less But I Don’t Want to Eliminate Their Right for Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write this little section here because it feels important to me and related enough. (Y’know, digital minimalism, creating apps &amp;amp; websites limits&amp;hellip; It made sense.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not a parent, I was a child once in the digital era, though. Does it make me an expert? No. But I can share my opinion like anybody else who lives online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a thin line between respecting your child’s right for privacy yet monitoring their phones and how they use it. I think having a conversation with your child about those things should help, they’re more understanding than you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can only provide tools, how they’re used depends on your family dynamic. Just please make sure to have a conversation with your child before introducing any drastic change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s apps like StayFocusd which are targeted towards families. As a parent, you can see which apps your child has on their device and put time limits on them. (For example, those apps will be blocked when they’re at school and after school activities and can only be used for an hour a day.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On iOS, you can achieve it on screen time menu. You can set screen time for family and set up parental control. There, you should be able to tweak settings and monitor your child accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another suggestion is to ask your child for their phone in order to set their social profiles as minors and put your credentials for their safety in case something goes wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;80% of this blog post was written in one sitting because I was fed up with people saying why doomscrolling isn’t as simple as uninstalling apps and why you should buy flip phones instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think you need to buy a new device that cost 130$ to 350+$. Not everyone can afford it, especially if your phone still works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution for being addicted to socials and doomscrolling is simple, it’s emotionally draining like any battle against addiction, nonetheless, it’s simple. I don’t think buying a new device makes the lack of dopamine easier, despite how nostalgic and sentimental it makes you feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So before rushing to spend your hard earned money on a new phone, I hope this article will give you a new perspective and a way to live your digital life more happily.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Privacy/security apps for daily use that are actually pretty?!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/my-privacy-and-security-apps/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/my-privacy-and-security-apps/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/p/my-privacy-and-security-apps/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Privacy/security apps for daily use that are actually pretty?!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;you&amp;rsquo;ve probably didn&amp;rsquo;t use some private/&lt;abbr title=&#34;Free Open Source Software&#34;&gt;FOSS&lt;/abbr&gt; apps and switched to a less private alternative. The &lt;abbr title=&#34;User Experience&#34;&gt;UX&lt;/abbr&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t quite as friendly than the apps you tried to replace, the &lt;abbr title=&#34;User Interface&#34;&gt;UI&lt;/abbr&gt; is outdated at best and doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for you at worst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking left and right for over a year to find apps that are private, secured and with a minimal and modern look. I&amp;rsquo;m not much into retro design unless it&amp;rsquo;s Windows XP aesthetics or KDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most is open source, but not all. The closed source don&amp;rsquo;t take information beside what you give and they work locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a security expert or anything of the sort, I just get my information from PrivacyGuides recommendations, alternativeto.net and my own trial and errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to further learn about privacy and security, please check PrivacyGuides and Privsec!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Horray!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No sharing links to not start fights, many can be found on F-Droid, most if not all can be found on the play-store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides my Android phone, which I use 99% of the time, I use a Mac and an iPad. As you can see, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get too far there, &lt;abbr title=&#34;Laugh out Loud&#34;&gt;LOL&lt;/abbr&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For design tools, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://leeashlee.github.io/p/my-design-and-art-apps/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Things I use to operate my system&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-shizuku&#34;&gt;1. Shizuku&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shizuku is an app that helps you run &lt;abbr title=&#34;Android Debug Bridge&#34;&gt;ADB&lt;/abbr&gt; through your phone on terminal apps such as Termux. You do need developer settings on to make it work, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy as pie to turn it on. I don&amp;rsquo;t use it for using &lt;abbr title=&#34;Android Debug Bridge&#34;&gt;ADB&lt;/abbr&gt; on my phone, but I use it to operate other tools I use all the time. If you use &lt;abbr title=&#34;Android Debug Bridge&#34;&gt;ADB&lt;/abbr&gt; a lot and are lazy to grab a PC, this app is for you. If you wanna use one the apps that uses Shizuku to run, this app is for you. If you love cats, this app is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-adguard&#34;&gt;2. Adguard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android, MacOS, iOS, Windows, Linux. (Works on browser too.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adguard is a &lt;abbr title=&#34; Domain Name System&#34;&gt;DNS&lt;/abbr&gt; blocking trackers and ads. Without it I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be alive right now. It&amp;rsquo;s encrypted, it&amp;rsquo;s simple, it&amp;rsquo;s cool. I use their &lt;abbr title=&#34; Domain Name System&#34;&gt;DNS&lt;/abbr&gt; address on Android (to keep my &lt;abbr title=&#34;Virtual Private Network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/abbr&gt; slot) and their Adguard app everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-app-ops&#34;&gt;3. App Ops&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;rsquo;s one app you must grab, grab this one with Shizuku. It uses Shizuku to operate, shows you permissions of all your apps, many permissions the Android settings doesn&amp;rsquo;t show you, you can put templates to disable permissions automatically everytime you download a new app, it shows you which permission an app used currently, clipboard monitor, usage monitor&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It saves life for me by checking which permissions any app uses and to disable them. It also helps with the clipboard monitor, since Samsung sure loves to break features. I also disable access to read my clipboard for all my apps, giving me a bit more control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did pay for this app to use all it&amp;rsquo;s features and I don&amp;rsquo;t regret it one bit. Just give it a try, see if you like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-caffeine&#34;&gt;4. Caffeine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not running a custom &lt;abbr title=&#34;Read-only memory&#34;&gt;ROM&lt;/abbr&gt; because it&amp;rsquo;s Samsung and Samsung is a meme, yet you really miss using Caffeine when cooking or reading articles or using walkthroughs for games, I gotchu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you don&amp;rsquo;t understand, Caffeine is something you can put on your notification menu and you can keep your phone from sleeping for an extended period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many &lt;abbr title=&#34;Read-only memory&#34;&gt;ROM&lt;/abbr&gt;s that use LineageOS as a base has Caffeine in them. However, you can download the same one and continue using Caffeine despite having a Samsung! You welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-sd-maid&#34;&gt;5. &lt;abbr title=&#34;Secure Digital&#34;&gt;SD&lt;/abbr&gt; Maid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, &lt;abbr title=&#34;Secure Digital&#34;&gt;SD&lt;/abbr&gt; maid removes junk from your storage. &lt;abbr title=&#34;Secure Digital&#34;&gt;SD&lt;/abbr&gt; card &amp;amp; main storage. It can also remove junk from your apps that just keeps space on your phone for no reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This app has been around since 2011, early Android releases! Respect your eldery apps, &lt;abbr title=&#34;Laugh out Loud&#34;&gt;LOL&lt;/abbr&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-shelter&#34;&gt;6. Shelter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you run GrapheneOS and you can run sandboxed apps systemlessly through profiles. I really recommend Shelter. It opens a Work Profile on your phone, there you can shelter certain apps and test them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s nice if you wanna sandbox certain apps and test their features or anything like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-swift-backup&#34;&gt;7. Swift Backup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another app that uses Shizuku to operate. It&amp;rsquo;s an app that replaces Google One backup and backup your phone. You can run on schedule, backup your phone on an &lt;abbr title=&#34;Secure Digital&#34;&gt;SD&lt;/abbr&gt; card or on the cloud. It has several cloud options, including self host. I personally connected a mega account that only backup my phone. I also use an &lt;abbr title=&#34;Secure Digital&#34;&gt;SD&lt;/abbr&gt; card to have a local backup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really recommend it as a phone backup alternative. It&amp;rsquo;s solid. It&amp;rsquo;s one of my favourite apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-untrack-me&#34;&gt;8. Untrack Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a simple app that automatically opens links on their front-end instances. You can set on which browser you want the front-ended link to be opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;security-tools&#34;&gt;Security Tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What I use to make my online life more secured.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-bitwarden&#34;&gt;1. Bitwarden&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android, Linux, iOS, MacOS, Windows and browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, my preferable option out of the two password managers, it&amp;rsquo;s much more stable, you can put and save your password everywhere, has an awesome system of secure notes (which I use a lot. What is it with me and anything notes?), you can save credit card information, addresses, connect email aliases, get username randomization. Honestly, go download Bitwarden now, you won&amp;rsquo;t regret it. Easy to sign up, easy to use, &lt;abbr title=&#34;Free Open Source Software&#34;&gt;FOSS&lt;/abbr&gt;, and just really cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-proton-pass&#34;&gt;2. Proton Pass&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android, Linux(?), iOS, MacOS, Windows, Browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A newer password manager and therefore less solid. I mostly use it for tests, I enjoy it the most on my iPad since it works the most smooth there. At browser and Android it&amp;rsquo;s 🫠. I like it for the email alias inside the system itself and the general design of the app. You can save notes and credit cards, but notes are way less advanced than Bitwarden so I barely use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I enjoy keeping my passwords inside Proton Pass because it has email alias systemlessly (therefore, less parties to trust) and because it looks nice and most of the time work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not patient testing shit out like me, use Bitwarden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-picocrypt&#34;&gt;3. Picocrypt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Linux, MacOS, Windows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but I still use &lt;abbr title=&#34;Secure Digital&#34;&gt;SD&lt;/abbr&gt; cards and flash drives outside of dual booting. Encrypting certain files is important to me. Besides feeling like a secret agent, I like to keep certain files hidden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picocrypt is a simple app that encrypts files you want wherever you want. It&amp;rsquo;s simple and minimal. If you need to encrypt files, instead of encrypting a certain drive, I recommend this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-yubico-authenticator&#34;&gt;4. Yubico Authenticator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but &lt;abbr title=&#34;2 Factor Authentication&#34;&gt;2FA&lt;/abbr&gt;s app annoys me. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to restore them if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the original device with you and are just pain 90% of the times. Sure, I can use my password managers to store my &lt;abbr title=&#34;2 Factor Authentication&#34;&gt;2FA&lt;/abbr&gt;s, but it always felt hard to understand and hard to navigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a person who loves physical things, Yubikey really hit that spot for me. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, easy, and you can carry it everywhere. Yubico Authenticator is a &lt;abbr title=&#34;2 Factor Authentication&#34;&gt;2FA&lt;/abbr&gt; app, but it operates with your Yubikey instead of your phone, which makes it easier for me to control if I suddenly switch phones or the app got uninstalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re the kind of person who loses keys a lot, or a regular human being, get a Yubikey spare. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you can connect another key to the &lt;abbr title=&#34;2 Factor Authentication&#34;&gt;2FA&lt;/abbr&gt; authenticator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working towards getting a spare key, so let&amp;rsquo;s hope nothing will happen to my Yubikey&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;browsers-proceed-to-make-the-biggest-browser-war&#34;&gt;Browsers (Proceed to make the biggest browser war)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I like using default browsers unless it&amp;rsquo;s Google Chrome or Safari on MacOS. Every browser is fine as long as you have patience to tweek settings everytime. If you like foxes, use Firefox, if you like super heroes, use Tor, if you&amp;rsquo;re feeling corageous, use Brave, if you&amp;rsquo;re feeling edgy, use Edge, if you wanna go to the Safari and you have iOS, use Safari. You welcome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-brave&#34;&gt;1. Brave&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android, iOS (Safari in disguise), Linux, MacOS, Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s my day to day browser on Android and Mac, I really enjoy it. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the best chromium browsers in terms of privacy. I don&amp;rsquo;t mind the crypto that much, you can opt out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;abbr title=&#34;Chief executive officer&#34;&gt;CEO&lt;/abbr&gt; slightly bothers me but that&amp;rsquo;s why I don&amp;rsquo;t use Brave everywhere and cut it every way I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-edge&#34;&gt;2. Edge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My go to browser on Windows at school or my Virtual Machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-firefox&#34;&gt;3. Firefox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android, iOS (Safari in disguise), Linux, MacOS, Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like Firefox, I mostly use it on Linux but I still like it. I used to be a regular Firefox user, and switched for unknown reason to Chromium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox on Android isn&amp;rsquo;t the best, so use a different browser on Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-safari&#34;&gt;4. Safari&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; iOS, MacOS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only use on my iPad because it&amp;rsquo;s actually pleasant there. I don&amp;rsquo;t vibe for Safari in my Mac for some reason, the minimal design doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for me on my Mac as much as it does on iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On iOS every browser is Safari apparently, so I just stick to the original. You can use &lt;abbr title=&#34;Duck Duck Go&#34;&gt;DDG&lt;/abbr&gt; as a default search so that&amp;rsquo;s nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-setter&#34;&gt;5. Setter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Setter when I need anonymous Google search or I need translation in various translation programs for comparison. It&amp;rsquo;s not really a browser, just a way to translate across all engines and search across various search engines. I recommend it for those reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-tor-browser&#34;&gt;6. Tor Browser&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android, Linux, Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not too sure if Tor Browser runs on Apple, so please let me know. I use the browser itself on Android while I use Tor on Brave for the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t use it to access the dark web, at least most of the time. I use Tor when I want to keep anonymous and search certain things or open links from others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have certain needs to be anonymous or you wanna be safe when opening links online, I recommend downloading Tor or use the Tor tab on Brave Browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;note-writing-and-document-writing&#34;&gt;Note Writing and Document Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t use a lot of noteapps, you just use too less. &amp;gt;:)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-ia-writer&#34;&gt;1. iA Writer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android, iOS, MacOS, Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually write this guide through iA writer! I&amp;rsquo;m a writer and it helps me a lot with writing stories, &lt;abbr title=&#34;Laugh out Loud&#34;&gt;LOL&lt;/abbr&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a Markdown writing tool with minimal design and distractions. You can write in device, share it to cloud, or write online anonymously through online collaboration. Online collaboration doesn&amp;rsquo;t add things directly in your original doc in device, but rather, once you stop the online collaboration, it saves you a new file in your device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally only use on Android and through online collaboration because buying 2 more versions for iOS and MacOS is rough for me. &lt;em&gt;Gotta save for those dolls, y&amp;rsquo;know?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any crazy permissions on Android. There is contacts permission but it works fine with the permission denied. If you wanna keep safe, block internet access, but &lt;abbr title=&#34;I Don&#39;t Know&#34;&gt;IDK&lt;/abbr&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to use Online Collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-goodnotes&#34;&gt;2. Goodnotes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; iOS, MacOS, Android, Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Goodnotes on my iPad to write my school-notes. It&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;abbr title=&#34;Free Open Source Software&#34;&gt;FOSS&lt;/abbr&gt;, but their privacy policy isn&amp;rsquo;t awful. I&amp;rsquo;m happy they give a &lt;abbr title=&#34;Too Long Don&#39;t Read&#34;&gt;TLDR&lt;/abbr&gt; of sorts at the beginning of their policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to their &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodnotes.com/privacy-policy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We never sell or rent your data or notebook content to third parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t access or collect data from your notebooks or documents without your permission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use limited, anonymized data to improve our services and meet legal obligations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We only share your data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you explicitly give us permission to do so and with the third parties specifically identified in this policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our customers, or others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we collect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic personal data (name, email, country) when you register.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anonymous statistical data (crash frequency, feature usage) to enhance the app experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you DO mind any of those terms, feel free to skip that one. Personally, I don&amp;rsquo;t mind. I wanted to add Goodnotes here because it&amp;rsquo;s something I genuinely use for University and I like it. If there&amp;rsquo;s any alternative of &lt;abbr title=&#34;Free Open Source Software&#34;&gt;FOSS&lt;/abbr&gt; notebook apps you can draw inside/use your apple pencil, please let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-noto&#34;&gt;3. Noto&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use this app to take quick notes and write random story ideas, thoughts, lyrics and projects I want to do. This app is &lt;abbr title=&#34;Free Open Source Software&#34;&gt;FOSS&lt;/abbr&gt;. The data is kept locally, I keep the data on my &lt;abbr title=&#34;Secure Digital&#34;&gt;SD&lt;/abbr&gt; card so I could redownload it on Noto once I&amp;rsquo;ll transfer to a different phone. There&amp;rsquo;s no automatic backup so you gotta remember to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-pages&#34;&gt;4. Pages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; iOS, MacOS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitches using default docs app, I&amp;rsquo;m bitches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use locally or connect it to iCloud, which encrypts your data if you want to. I do connect to iCloud for seamless connection between my Mac and iOS. This is how I traditionally edit my docs when I&amp;rsquo;m done with writing through iA Writer on Android or Online Collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do what you may.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-qt-notes&#34;&gt;5. Qt Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really Kawaii app you can open &amp;ldquo;notebooks&amp;rdquo;, decorate them and add to do lists and notes in them. The design and overall app is very minimal. I use it for more dedicated to do lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The permissions are minimal. It asks for coarse location but it works fine when not allowing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data of your notes are saved locally and are not moving with you when you download the app on a new phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;abbr title=&#34;Free Open Source Software&#34;&gt;FOSS&lt;/abbr&gt; though, &lt;abbr title=&#34;If I Remember Correctly&#34;&gt;IIRC&lt;/abbr&gt;. If you want &lt;abbr title=&#34;Free Open Source Software&#34;&gt;FOSS&lt;/abbr&gt;, use Noto. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-streaming&#34;&gt;Video Streaming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t watch TV or Netflix, but I do like to watch YouTube and when I have the attention span: Anime and K-Dramas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-cloudstream&#34;&gt;1. CloudStream&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a nice looking app with several instances where you can watch anime and K-dramas. I think I saw western TV shows there too. It&amp;rsquo;s nice and free to use. It&amp;rsquo;s also Open Source, so check it out and decide for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-libretube&#34;&gt;2. LibreTube&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A beautiful app that runs Piped instances. For me it&amp;rsquo;s much nicer than PipeTube. It looks nicer, you can block sponsorships and it looks like a genuine modern YouTube app. I usually open videos I kept on Watch Later on my YouTube app through LibreTube, making the experience easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instances can crash at times though, which can make the experience annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-piped-on-the-browser&#34;&gt;3. Piped on The Browser&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Everywhere that runs a browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a smoother YouTube experience, I recommend using your favourite Piped instance on the browser. You gotta download the SponsorBlock extention if you wanna skip sponsorships though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-apps&#34;&gt;More Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-mupdf-viewer&#34;&gt;1. Mu&lt;abbr title=&#34;Portable Document Format&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/abbr&gt; Viewer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;abbr title=&#34;Free Open Source Software&#34;&gt;FOSS&lt;/abbr&gt; &lt;abbr title=&#34;Portable Document Format&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/abbr&gt; Viewer. That&amp;rsquo;s it. You can view &lt;abbr title=&#34;Portable Document Format&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/abbr&gt;s in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-paseo&#34;&gt;2. Paseo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can count steps and be happy. I use it everyday to count my steps, nice and easy brainer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-proton-mail&#34;&gt;3. Proton Mail&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android, iOS, your browser, any email client you have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty and private email service. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you heard about Proton. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t switch from G-mail yet and you want a fast experience without ads, just open an account. Really, you won&amp;rsquo;t regret it. Look how pretty Proton is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-proton-vpn&#34;&gt;4. Proton &lt;abbr title=&#34;Virtual Private Network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;abbr title=&#34;Operating System&#34;&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Android, iOS, Linux, MacOS, Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you need a &lt;abbr title=&#34;Virtual Private Network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/abbr&gt;? That leaks everywhere unless it&amp;rsquo;s iOS? Do you need a &lt;abbr title=&#34;Virtual Private Network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/abbr&gt; with Netshield to block ads and trackers and Secure Core? Well, Proton&lt;abbr title=&#34;Virtual Private Network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/abbr&gt; is your friend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know what a &lt;abbr title=&#34;Virtual Private Network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/abbr&gt; is, you probably do but I wanna sound smart. &lt;abbr title=&#34;Virtual Private Network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/abbr&gt; stands for Virtual Private Network. It sends your internet traffic to the &lt;abbr title=&#34;Virtual Private Network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/abbr&gt; provider instead of your internet provider. Yes, you can watch Netflix all over the world, as long as Netflix works there and the &lt;abbr title=&#34; Domain Name System&#34;&gt;DNS&lt;/abbr&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t leak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you use &lt;abbr title=&#34;Virtual Private Network&#34;&gt;VPN&lt;/abbr&gt; when connected to free WiFi!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
